Eden, hope everybody's doing all right.
Um, you know, hopefully off to a decent
start here. Um, say kind of the first
round honestly played out the way we
sort of anticipated. I think there ended
up being I don't know like seven
tackles, two guards, couple
quarterbacks, five or six receivers,
couple backs, and then 14 players on
defense or whatever it was. Um, so, um,
looked at a couple different scenarios.
Um, you know, potentially moving up, uh,
and then, you know, I think moving two
spots. It was just more of semantics and
more than positioning more than anything
else. Um, you know, it felt like there
potentially could be, uh, you know, some
interest in the player. So, we felt
like, all right, we'll just move a
couple spots, essentially give up a
fifth round pick is essentially what the
difference is when you actually do the
math. um you know to get a player who I
think you all just spoke with him but I
would say I mean the things that stand
out about him I mean toughness,
violence, physicality,
his playing style, his intelligence.
I mean a basically guy wants to step on
your throat in every play. So which I
would say sort of embodies what our
football team is about. The way we play
intense, violent, physical, like we're
going to run the football this year. um
you know was an area that we felt like
we wanted to and needed to improve here
in the offseason. Hopefully we've done
that and um I would say Big Red is
hopefully you know a part of that. Like
where's he going to play? Like who the
hell knows? I mean we'll figure out like
who the best five guys are and you know
put the group out there that we think is
going to help us the most. Understanding
that we'll probably need eight to 10
guys on the offensive line here at some
point. So um you know he's a player that
again a good example transfer up. So,
started at obviously a lower level, then
transferred over to Georgia Tech and had
a good career there. Um, you know, was
at the Senior Bowl. Um, you know, we
spent a little bit of time with him
here, um, in the spring. I mean, Cole
went down there, worked him out. Um, so
I mean, he's a player like I think the
whole building collectively felt
strongly about. So, you know, it sort of
worked out the way that we had hoped it
would. So, you know, excited to get him
here and we'll be back to the drawing
board here tomorrow. Um, I think we got
38 uh what 59 kind of like picking third
round. Just got moved down there a
little bit. So, try to take advantage of
our opportunities here tomorrow. Um,
with those picks. I'm sure we'll get
some calls and, you know, we'll kind of
see what makes sense relative to moving
back or sitting and picking. So, just
kind of take it here, you know, one pick
at a time, but you know, definitely
excited about Keelin and the things that
he brings to the table. So take some
questions.
>> When you look at did you have a specific
moment in meeting him or or watching him
that that you had conviction yourself
that he was a guy that that you really
liked?
>> Oh yeah. When you put the tape on? I
mean everybody that watched him I mean
your notes basically say physical,
tough, strong, good to run blocker, good
at the point of attack. Um he's probably
more athletic than maybe people think he
is. Um, he's got some technique things
that he can certainly clean up, which I
think one of the things with the workout
sometimes you're trying to have a player
maybe simulate some of the things that
they're going to be asked to do. So, can
they take the coaching? How do they
apply the coaching? Uh, I mean, it
wasn't a player like the makeup on this
guy is like elite. like a couple of the
metrics that we have in our when we
grade players. I mean in like four or
five categories like there were one
player there's one player in a draft
that our scouts graded the way that they
did and it was him. So like that was
like okay we didn't talk to him at the
combine because we didn't need to like
and we might not even interviewed him at
the senior bowl because we didn't need
to. So, I mean, there was a couple touch
points here and there we felt like, but
just put the tape on, watch the guy
play. And I'd say like the program that
Coach Key runs down there at Georgia
Tech, we got a lot of respect for their
program. I mean, Coach Key is a former
offensive lineman. Um, and again, I
think like Big Red, like who he is is
emblematic in like what you saw tonight.
I mean, the basic guy was an Airbnb with
him and his wife and that was pretty
much it. You know, you see some of these
other draft parties, some of you know,
you got it's look like a circus. I mean,
this guy's all ball. He's all football.
Doesn't really care about anything else.
Wants to punch people in the mouth. Yep,
that works here. So, I mean, that's what
you see on tape, which is, I'd say, part
of the intrigue with the player.
>> How valuable is it to you guys that he's
comfortable playing all three positions?
>> Yeah, we'll see. I mean, he'll probably
play wherever like he needs a play. So,
I'd say all three inside guys. Again,
we've talked about this. You got some
guys that are center only, some guys
that are guard only, some guys that can
play all three spots. So, we'll see how
it goes. I mean, he's played mostly
right guard. I mean, kind of put his
hand on the ball there a little bit at
the senior bowl. So, I mean, where's he
going to play? I mean, we'll see. Like,
nobody knows. So, we'll figure that out
as we go.
>> Some guys um they overcome adversity,
and he did. He won the Pichello award,
got through that car accident, had a
pretty pretty bad foot injury. When you
see a player like that that's already
been through something, what does that
tell you about the mental toughness that
you hope for?
>> Yeah, I think it kind of speaks to his
personality, Erin. I think that was like
the appealing thing about this player. I
mean, you alluded to the accident that
he went through, but like I said
mentioned a little bit earlier, talk
about a transfer up. I mean, he didn't
start at at the biggest program. I mean,
nobody has ever heard of the program
that he started and then he went to
Georgia Tech and he made an impact. So,
I think that's speaks to who he is as an
individual, his mindset, and it really
is emblematic of what this program, the
foundation, the principles that that we
talk about, that Demo talks about, that
I talk about, that the players talk
about, that we want to have in our
players because in the end, like you're
going to need that on Sundays. So, I
mean, it's he's a really he's a great
kid. Um, cares a lot about football.
He's overcome some things. Um, you know,
I think his wife is a big influence in
his life. Um, I think Coach Key has been
a big influence on him. Um, like I said,
we have a lot of respect for Coach Key
and the program that he runs and and
what he's about. And look, they won, I
don't know, nine or 10 games or whatever
it was. And they probably beat some
teams that they like nobody thought they
should beat, but they have a lot of
belief um in themselves. Um, and I think
Big Red certainly falls into that
category.
>> The offensive line's shortcomings this
last season. Uh just what's the timeline
in getting him in to the lineup?
>> I mean the best five guys will play. So
like whoever those guys are. I mean
we're not going to put any timelines on
anybody. So whenever they're ready,
they're ready and we'll figure out like
who's going to be out there. I mean it
might start one way and then it might
shift. I mean there's a lot of things
that can happen. So I mean we don't put
any timelines in anybody. I mean the
players ultimately determine what the
timeline is. So when a player's ready,
we'll put them out there and if that's
the best option, then that's a guy
that's going to play.
James Lifford uh obviously he's an alum
and football player for Georgia Tech.
Did that help at all with the scouting
process? Obviously you just got all the
schools, but uh did was that helpful at
all?
>> Yeah, I mean I think other than like
them maybe giving more to the alumni
fund. I mean I probably wasn't too much
into it. So I mean uh you know I mean
James does a good job. I think the
scouting group does a phenomenal job. I
mean like the pro staff, the college
staff. I mean essentially like when we
were going through the draft, we were
looking at each team. Okay, what are
their needs? what do we think they're
going to do? And whoever had that team
had an answer in a heartbeat. And
honestly, it played out exactly the way
they thought. So, I mean, I have a lot
of respect and appreciation for our
group. They work really, really hard.
They take a lot of pride. They care.
They're informed.
They understand their teams and they
provide uh incredible information so
that ultimately we can make good
decisions for the organization. So,
that's the most important thing
>> on the economy board. on the SC report
it talks about how great of a run
blocker he is and how he's able to maul
the you know defense flying in front of
him but they said that some of his
weaknesses is pass blocking how much can
covage help him with that
>> yeah I don't know who said that or like
what scouting reports like we're reading
or who we're relying on I mean all
players have areas that they can improve
and fix so I mean doesn't matter who
they are what they are so again I don't
know what Scott report who said that I
mean we don't really care what we care
about is what they do when they walk in
our program and what what we're going to
ask them to do. All you want to do is
see a player like take coaching,
improve, and apply what we're teaching.
That's all we care about. And
>> at the same he took a couple of snaps at
center. Were you all able to observe
that? What did you think?
>> Uh yeah. I mean, I think sometimes it's
probably hard to extrapolate too much,
you know, when a guy just goes down
there in the Senior Bowl for three days
and, you know, has a couple snaps and
like, well, you're making a projection
based off of that. So, um, again, we'll
see how that goes. I mean, if a guy can
put his hand in the ball, then okay,
what does that look like? Then the
communication that's involved with it.
So, again, like when a player walks in
the building, like we'll put things on
his plate, see what they can handle, um,
and see how quickly they can adapt and
adjust to what we're asking them to do.
>> Nick, was was the the interaction with
with this kid at the senior bowl? Was
this sort of like the cool to grow on
top from what y'all seen on the tape or
it just was this sort of like put the
period behind this is the way you want
him on your draft board?
>> Uh yeah, I mean I think we grade the
player in the fall and you assign a
grade and there wasn't a lot of
variation or deviation like after the
season. I think one thing you have to be
careful about is okay, you spent all
this time in the fall and then okay, you
start making adjustments or changes
based on like senior bowl and all that.
So I think our scouts our grades were
pretty consistent throughout. Um, so
you're just evaluating the player,
evaluating the performance. Um,
honestly,
I'd be careful to put too much stock in
a senior bowl either way because again,
it's a short snapshot, small snapshot.
So, but everything is all-encompassing
at the end. Tape, senior bowl, combine,
pro day, workout, if you do a visit,
those zoom, like whatever the case may
be. So, you try to accumulate as much
information and create a profile on the
player as possible. and then just try to
take that information and say here's
what we think we have in a player
understanding, you know, there might be
some deviation or variation when they
get here. So, it's all part of the
process, all part of the evaluation.
>> To follow up on S's question about co
obviously he met with uh co-op and went
through a little workout. How much does
that interaction help I guess the
evaluation process for you guys?
>> Yeah, it's a part of it. So, we do that
with all of our coaches like we had a
number of our coaches out in the spring.
So whether it's a private workout,
whether they go to the pro day, I mean,
every team has the ability to basically
zoom with a player three times. So you
have different touch points and a lot of
that is like football. So yeah, we like
we value their opinion. Hey, what do you
think? What information are you
gathering? Is it different than maybe
what we already had or something new? So
like we value our coaches and their
opinions and what they think of the
player at the various touch points.
Again, it's a snapshot. It's not the
only like we're go making a decision
based off of that. It's an accumulation
over time. Um, and I'd say with this
particular player, it's pretty
consistent what we're getting in return.
>> Yeah, I know you mentioned you'll let
you know the position play itself out.
Was the fact that he is multiple. Was
that intriguing for you guys or or do
you all envision something?
>> I'd say just generally speaking any
player if they have some degree of
position flexibility or versatility. I
mean, there's value in that. Again, even
going back to tackle, some tackles are
left tackle only, some are right tackle
only, some can pensively swing and do
both. So again, you try to put the
player in a position to see if if they
can handle that assignment. You might
think theoretically, oh yeah, they
should be able to do it or he did it
here, but then come to find out, you go
down the road. I mean, I'd say just past
experience, I've seen it happen both
ways. like, oh, you think this guy
should just be able to project inside or
he played left tackle, should have no
business, no problem playing right
tackle, and then you put him over there
in the right side and it's a disaster.
It's like, well, let's just keep him
over there where he belongs. So, again,
try to see what a player can handle and
ultimately try to fit him in best where
like they're comfortable, we're
comfortable, um, and then go from there.